Avinash Kumar

Cloud Engineer & JavaScript Developer https://avinashvidyarthi.github.io avinashvidyarthi@gmail.com +91 7765034079

I'm a Cloud Engineer with 2 years of experience in GCP and AWS. As a Cloud Engineer/Architect certified by GCP & AWS, I am well-versed in designing and deploying scalable cloud-based solutions. In addition to cloud technologies, I have knowledge and experience in web development using JavaScript and NodeJS.

Experience

SR RESEARCH ASSOCIATE – CLOUDTHAT (JAN 2023 – PRESENT)

- Leading successful cloud infrastructure creation projects, ensuring scalability and costefficiency
- Led seamless cloud migration projects with minimal downtime and disruptions.
- Played a key role in pre-sales tasks, securing new projects and building client relationships.
- Implemented solutions that align with client goals, maximizing the value of cloud services.

PROGRAMMER ANALYST – COGNIZANT (JULY 2021 – JAN 2023)

- Working as a frontline GCP support for Google as a client.
- Working with managed products of GCP. Eg: App Engine, Cloud Run, Cloud SQL, etc.
- Got certified as Professional Cloud Architect GCP.
- Working on automating the workflow.

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER – ZIGNUTS TECHNOLAB (SEPT 2020 – JULY 2021)

- Worked on backend with technologies like NodeJS, SailsJS, AWS on project Silvatree
- Implemented backend referral scenario for the project
- Used many AWS products like S3, Cognito, SNS, SQS, etc.
- Worked with serverless architecture using AWS lambda
- Worked with various DBs like MySQL & MongoDB

Technical Skills <a> @

- Google Cloud Platform, Amazon Web Services, Basic Terraform
- Html5, CSS3, Angular 2+, Bootstrap, JavaScript
- NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB
- WebRTC, Git

Educational Qualification @

Degree/Year	Institute	Specialization	Marks/CGPA
B. Tech (CSE) in 2021	Gandhi Institute of Engineering & Technology University, Gunupur	Computer Science & Engineering	9.18 CGPA
+2 Science in 2016	Kanhaiya Lal Sahoo College, Nawada, Bihar	PCM	70.0%
10 th in 2014	Tirthankar Mahaveer Vidya Mandir, Pawapuri, Bihar	Social Science, English, Hindi, Math, Science	9.8 CGPA

Project Details

Name of the Project	E-Pariksha
Language Used	Angular 8, NodeJS, ExpressJs, MongoDB, Cloudflare
Description	This portal makes use of web technology for creating and conducting online MCQ contest.
Website Link	https://e-pariksha.herokuapp.com

Name of the Project	Callz
Language Used	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SocketIO, WebRTC
Description	One to one video call/chat room portal.
Website Link	https://callz.herokuapp.com/

More projects can be found at my portfolio: https://avinashvidyarthi.github.io

Certifications and Achievements @

- Awarded "Rookie of the Quarter" for Mar-June 2023 Quarter at CloudThat
- Certified as Solutions Architect Associate by AWS
- Certified as Professional Cloud Architect & Associate Cloud Engineer from Google Cloud.
- Trainer at 2-day workshop on web development organized by Odisha Oracle Users Group at GIET University, Gunupur
- Member of the team which developed and maintained website for annual branch fest of CSE – AVYAKT: 2018

Place:	
Date:	(Avinash Kumar)